<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section 
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xml:lang="en" xml:id="majisti.introduction.userContribution" 
    version="5.0">
    
    <title>User Contribution</title>
    
    <para>User contribution is a big part of Majisti. In fact, the entire
        library is driven by it since it only provides tools for modularity.
        With no modules contributed well... no focus on business modeling is
        really achieved! </para>
    
    <para>We believe that concentrating on one simple and very concrete tasks is
        what is the easiest for developpers and this is why most people are
        making web applications on the fly - maybe using a framework - but still
        coding until it is done. Using abstraction is harder, requires more time
        and most of the time the end customer does not really care about the
        abstraction used within since usually that abstraction can even be used
        again for his competitors! Business modeling is more interresting since
        it is the process of designing something new, based on the current
        knowledge and experience. Nevertheless, business modeling usually covers
        so much of areas that must be focussed on the end user and this leads us
        to our main concern: how can we achieve everything without going
        insane?</para>
    
    <para>User contribution. By using modularity, most of the business model is
        built around the knowledge of such plugin avaibility. Business modelin
        gis oriented in popular trends and the concrete complexity of real world
        applicability is solved by tweaking those contributed modules. In fact,
        after designing those models, the only thing left is building the actual
        application and its layout, provided you don't use the default templates
        shipped with the standard distribution! The key is to concentrate on
        business modeling. </para>
    <blockquote>
        <para>The key is to concentrate on business modeling.</para>
    </blockquote>
    
    <para>Majisti plans to use a proposal system which promotes user contributed
        modules to allow the most popular ideas to climb up the ladder as fast
        and possible and gather the maximum number of developers.</para>
</section>
