<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section 
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xml:lang="en" xml:id="majisti.i18n.localeSession" 
    version="5.0">
    
    <title>Locale Session</title>

    <para>The &lt;<classname>LocaleSession</classname> class provides a variety
        of functions meant to ease the management a multilingual application.
        It allows automatic handling of the application's supported languages
        with the help of a &lt;<classname>Zend_Session_Namespace</classname>. </para>
    <para>With a locale session object, it is possible to know the current
        locale of an application, the default locale, all the supported
        locales, if a locale is supported, etc. It also provides behaviours to
        add locales, switch between locales and reset the locales to the
        default ones found in the configuration.</para>
    <para>In order to supply supported languages to the locale session
        singleton, simply list all of the supported languages in the
        configuration using the following
        syntax:<programlisting>plugins.i18n.supportedLocales[] = es
plugins.i18n.supportedLocales[] = fr
plugins.i18n.supportedLocales[] = ch</programlisting></para>
    <para>As you may notice in the above example, there is no explicitly
        defined default language. In that case, Majisti sets the default locale
        to English (en). It is important to understand the difference between
        supported languages and the default language. You may wonder "how can
        English be the default locale when it's not even marked as supported in
        the configuration file?". Well, the answer is quite simple. You are
        allowed to put no supported locales at all. Majisti sets the default
        language in this case to English, as stated before. This means that the
        default locale and the supported locales are two different concepts.
        The supported locales do not include the default one. Think of them as
        "other than the default one" supported locales.</para>
    <para>To define the default locale of you application, the configuration
        setting is quite similar to the one of defining the supported locales.
        All there is to do is add the following line in the configuration
        file:<programlisting>plugins.i18n.defaultLocale = fr</programlisting></para>
</section>
