<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<section 
    xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" 
    xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
    xmlns:xi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XInclude" 
    xml:lang="en" xml:id="majisti.introduction.userContribution" 
    version="5.0">
    
    <title>User Contribution</title>
    
    <para>User contribution is a big part of Majisti. In fact, the entire library
        is driven by it since it only provides tools for modularity. With no modules
        contributed well... no modularity is really achieved!
    </para>
    
    <para>
        We believe that concentrating on one simple and very concrete tasks is what
        is the easiest for developpers hence most people are making websites on the fly
        - maybe using a framework - but still coding until it is done. Using abstraction is harder
        and requires more time and most of the time the end customer for the website does not
        really care about the abstraction used within his website since usually that abstraction
        can even be used again for his competitors! Business modeling is what usually
        is the most interresting since its the making of something new, based
        on the current knowledge and experience in the ways of creating something by
        expending that knowledge and gaining more experience. But business modeling usually covers
        so much of areas where everything must be focussed on the end user. So, how
        can we achieve everything without going insane?
    </para>
    
    <para>User contribution. Very well known by the open source community.
        By using modularity most of the business model is solved up with already contributed
        modules which are already proven successfull and working and the use case modeling
        sums up of configuring those modules and coding the models related to that business.
        In fact, after designing those models, the only thing left is building the actual website
        and its layout, provided you don't use the default templates shipped with the standard
        distribution! <emphasis>The key is to concentrate on business modeling</emphasis>.
    </para>
    
    <para>Majisti is using a proposal system which promotes user contributed modules
        so that the most popular ideas climb up the ladder as fast and possible
        and gather the maximum number of developers. With your reputation it is even possible
        to feedback on a proposed component by suggesting more interesting ideas.
        More on that on the actual website.
    </para>
</section>
